(SNARLING)
It's the only way.
No one else knows.
You gonna tell 'em?
Not till after.
We have to do it today.
It has to be quiet.
You got a plan?
We tell her we need to talk.
Away from the others.
Just ain't us, man.
No. No, it isn't.
We do this,
we avoid a fight.
No one else dies.
Okay.
We need someone else.
I'll talk to him.
I'll do it.
-I'll go with you.
-No.
Just me.
(FABRIC RIPPING)
Just looking for a little vacation.
Best dope I ever had was in a mattress.
Nothing.
This place must have been no fun at all.
We need your help.
(LAUGHS)
Do you even know why
you do the things you do?
The choices you make?
If we give The Governor Michonne,
Woodbury stands down.
I don't like it,
but it's what needs to be done.
We need to make it quiet.
We need your help with that.
You ain't told any of the others, huh?
Just Hershel, Daryl and you.
Huh.
The inner circle.
I'm honored.
(CHUCKLES)
You know,
when we'd go out on runs,
he'd bash somebody's skull,
slash somebody's throat,
and he'd say, "Never waste a bullet."
I always thought it was just an excuse.
You go on.
Give him that girl.
He ain't gonna kill her, you know.
He's just gonna do things to her.
Probably take out one of her eyes.
Both of 'em, most likely.
You'd let that happen
for a shot?
Whew.
You're cold as ice, Officer Friendly.
You're gonna need wire,
not rope.
Wire. Nothing she could chew through.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh.
You know something?
You're right.
I don't know why I do the things I do.
Never did.
I'm a damn mystery to me.
But I know you, Rick.
Yeah, I thought a lot about you.
You ain't got the spine for it.
We need to get her
to the Governor by noon.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
-(WALKERS SNARLING)
-(MAGGIE SHOUTING)
-CARL: Hey! Come on! Over here!
-(POTS CLANGING)
-Hey! Come on!
-MAGGIE: Over here!
Hey! Right here!
Over here!
-Come on!
-Here! Here!
CARL: Come on!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
DARYL: Come on, let's go.
They try to drive up to the gate again,
maybe some blown tires will stop them.
-That's a good idea.
-It was Michonne's.
MICHONNE: We don't have to win.
We just have to make their getting at us
more trouble than it's worth.
(GATE CLOSES)
Hey.
Let's go.
Ain't no way.
CAROL: What?
Nothing.
What happened here?
We got any whiskey?
Hell, I'd even drink vodka.
Go to hell, Merle.
(LAUGHS)
Are you with us?
Sure.
I'm not talking about
occupying the same space.
Are you with us?
I'm here for my brother.
Well, he's here for us.
It's not time to do shots.
It's time to pick a damn side.
(LAUGHS)
You ain't like you was back in the camp,
a little mouse running around,
scared of her own shadow.
It wasn't my shadow, it was my husband's.
Well, you don't seem
scared of nothing anymore.
I'm not.
Hmm.
You're a late bloomer.
Maybe you are, too.
Hey.
You seen Merle around?
He say he was sorry yet?
'Cause he is.
He's gonna make it right.
I'm gonna make him.
There's got to be a way.
Just needs to be a little
forgiveness is all.
He tied me to a chair,
beat me and threw a walker in the room.
Maybe I could call it even.
But he...
He took Maggie to a man
who terrorized her,
humiliated her.
I care more about her
than I care about me.
(METAL CLINKING)
Merle.
You down here?
Hey, little brother.
What the hell?
I was just about to holler back at ya.
What you doing down here?
Just looking for a little, uh,
crystal meth.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Shit will mess my life up
when everything is going so sweet, right?
(LAUGHS)
You talk to Rick yet?
Yeah. Oh, yeah. I'm in.
But, uh,
he ain't got the stomach for it.
He's gonna buckle. You know that, right?
Yeah.
If he does, he does.
You want him to?
Whatever he says goes.
(SCOFFS) Man.
Do you even possess
a pair of balls, little brother?
Are they even attached?
I mean, if they are,
do they belong to you?
You used to call people like that sheep.
What happened to you?
What happened with you and Glenn
and Maggie?
I've done worse.
You need to grow up.
Things are different now.
Your people look at me
like I'm the devil...
Grabbing up those lovebirds
like that, huh?
Now y'all want to do
the same damn thing I did.
Snatch someone up
and deliver them to the Governor,
just like me.
Yeah.
People do what they
got to do or they die.
Can't do things without
people anymore, man.
(SCOFFS)
Maybe these people need
somebody like me around, huh?
Do their dirty work.
The bad guy.
Yeah, maybe that's how it is now, huh?
How does that hit you?
I just want my brother back.
Get out of here, man.
HERSHEL: "Thou shalt not be afraid
"for the terror by night,
"nor for the arrow that flieth by day,
"nor for the pestilence
that walketh in darkness,
"nor for the destruction
"that wasteth at noonday.
"A thousand shall fall at thy side
"and 10,000 at thy right hand,
"but it shall not come nigh thee.
"Only with thine eyes
"shalt thou behold
"and see the reward of the wicked.
"Surely he shall deliver thee
"from the snare of the fowler,
"and from the noisome pestilence."
You're not there.
She's not there.
HERSHEL: "He shall cover thee
"and under his wings shalt thou trust.
"There shall no evil befall thee,
"neither shall any plague
come nigh thy dwelling."
You okay?
What I wouldn't do
to keep you two safe.
(DOOR OPENS)
Rick?
What you're about to do...
I can't.
I won't.
MICHONNE: So where is it?
MERLE: Around the corner.
We got to clear some walkers,
then get the others
down here to barricade it.
A breach like this could
be an open invitation to the Governor.
He's not much for subtlety.
(SNARLING)
You want to take your chances?
(GRUNTS)
Governor made Rick an offer.
Turn you over and we all give peace
a chance.
I agree with you, though.
He would have blinked.
But not you.
(SCOFFS)
I'm being straight with you.
You were straight
when you led me into the tombs.
Okay, maybe I wasn't straight.
You put a bag over my head.
I got it done.
He wouldn't have.
Keep moving.
He was a guy that came back
for me on that rooftop.
Nah.
It's all on me.
You know?
I figure that's why I was back there
in the first place.
Do the dirty work.
(WALKER GROWLING)
(LAUGHING)
May I?
I'll take that as a yes.
(GROWLING)
(LAUGHS)
Oh!
You know what?
I'd figured you would have run.
Wanted my sword back before I get away.
(LAUGHS)
It may go down that way.
But if I were you,
I wouldn't get my hopes up.
Move.
It's off. We'll take our chances.
I'm not saying it was the wrong call,
but this is definitely the right one.
What's wrong?
I can't find Merle or Michonne.
They've gone.
Come on.
He was in here.
Said he was looking for drugs.
Said a lot of things, actually.
Like what?
Said that you were gonna change your mind.
Here we go.
Yeah, he took her here. They mixed it up.
Damn it! I'm going after him.
-You can't track for shit.
-Then the both of us.
No, just me.
I said I'd go and I'll go.
Plus they're gonna come back here.
You need to be ready.
Your family, too.
I want to be with my brother.
My brother, he wants to be in the prison.
This little trip...
Maybe it'll keep that place standing.
If I pull it off, maybe all is forgiven.
That's a whole lot of maybes.
You got to play the hand you're dealt.
I only got one.
You talk about the weight
of what you have to do,
how you can handle it.
A bad man,
someone truly evil,
they're light as a feather.
They don't feel a thing.
I've killed 16 men
since all this went down.
-Let's go.
-(WALKERS SNARLING)
Look at what that bastard's done.
Look at us.
He's one man.
There'll be others like him.
There always have been.
I know. It's like the walkers.
There's nothing we can do.
When you gave me this...
I didn't fully understand what it meant.
Such a simple thing.
I know what it means now.
I know what it takes.
I want to marry Maggie.
And we don't have to have a wedding.
I don't even know if we'll last the week.
But I want her to know
before...
Who knows?
You have my blessing.
Thank you.
All right.
I think we're good.
Yeah, we're great.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
Come on.
-(ENGINE STARTS)
-Yeah!
That's the deal.
-(CAR ALARM BLARING)
-Oh, shit.
(WALKERS SNARLING)
Merle!
Come on, Merle!
Okay. Okay.
-(ALARM CHIRPS)
-(BLARING STOPS)
Argh!
Come on.
Let's go!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
So is this your thing, then?
You take out the trash?
Don't be so hard on yourself, darlin'.
The Governor, Rick,
anyone who needs
their piss bucket emptied
and you come a-running.
(LAUGHS)
Things are different for your brother.
Yeah, they are.
Rick says jump
and he wants to know how high.
Mmm-mmm. Rick needs him.
Respects him.
He didn't ask him to do
this little job, now, did he?
No, 'cause he wants it done.
You keep telling yourself that.
The truth is this could
have been your shot.
With your skills, a whole new beginning.
But you choose to stay on the outside.
No one's gonna mourn you,
not even Daryl.
He's got a new family.
You keep trying to get under my skin,
I'm gonna cut that tongue out.
Your buddy's turning you over
'cause he's trying to save his own ass.
You're as much on the outside
as I am, girl.
Maybe.
But once the Governor's done with me,
at least I won't have to live with myself.
(WALKERS GROWLING)
(BONES CRUNCH)
You said you killed 16 men
since this thing started?
You ever kill anyone before?
No.
And how about before Woodbury?
Before you met him?
Huh.
So he saves your life,
cleans you up,
fed you a line of bullshit.
Why would you kill somebody else for him?
You know, we can go back.
(CHUCKLES)
Ain't happening.
Both of us.
We can just go back.
I can't go back.
Don't you understand that?
I can't.
Why?
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
You go back with them.
Get ready for what's next.
I got something I got to do on my own.
(SNARLING)
Hey!
Where's my brother?
You kill him?
He let me go.
Don't let anyone come after me.
(MUSIC PLAYING OVER RADIO)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(TURNS UP VOLUME)
MAN: Where's it coming from?
Come on, come on. With me.
MAN: We'll have to spread out!
MAN: You two with me.
Walkers!
MAN: All over!
(MEN SHOUTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Hey, over there.
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTING)
You leave him to me!
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
(SHOUTS)
(SCREAMING)
-(ARM CRACKS)
-(GROANS)
(CHOKING)
(COUGHS)
I ain't gonna beg.
I ain't begging you.
No.
-Hey.
Carl was looking for you.
He found me.
I think we should head over.
Rick has something to say.
Uh, just...
One more thing before that.
Here.
Yes.
When I met with the Governor,
he offered me a deal.
He said...
He said he would leave us alone
if I gave him Michonne.
And I was gonna do that...
To keep us safe.
I changed my mind.
But now Merle took Michonne
to fulfill the deal
and Daryl went to stop him,
and I don't know if it's too late.
I was wrong not to tell you.
And I'm sorry.
What I said last year,
that first night after the farm,
it can't be like that.
It can't.
What we do, what we're willing to do,
who we are, it's not my call.
It can't be.
I couldn't sacrifice one of us
for the greater good
because, because we are the greater good.
We're the reason we're still here, not me.
This is life and death.
How you live,
how you die, it isn't up to me.
I'm not your governor.
We choose to go. We choose to stay.
We stick together.
We vote.
We can stay and we can fight,
or we can go.
(WALKER MUNCHING)
(WALKER SNARLING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(WALKER MUNCHING)
(WALKER RASPING)
(CROSSBOW FIRING)
(CRYING)
(SOBBING)
-DARYL: No!
-(GROWLING)
(SOBBING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTS)
-(GROWLS)
-(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(SOBBING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)